import { QuestionType, SubjectCode } from "./utils";

const subject_code = SubjectCode.BUSINESS_STUDIES;
export const BusinessStudies: QuestionType[] = [
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "What is the term for the process of planning, organizing, and controlling resources to achieve specific goals?",
    option_a: "Marketing",
    option_b: "Management",
    option_c: "Accounting",
    option_d: "Entrepreneurship",
    correct_option: "Management",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text: "In business, what does ROI stand for?",
    option_a: "Return on Investment",
    option_b: "Rate of Interest",
    option_c: "Revenue of Income",
    option_d: "Risk of Inflation",
    correct_option: "Return on Investment",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "What is the term for the legal document that specifies the conditions under which a business operates?",
    option_a: "Business Plan",
    option_b: "Memorandum of Association",
    option_c: "Partnership Deed",
    option_d: "Articles of Incorporation",
    correct_option: "Memorandum of Association",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "What type of economic system is characterized by private ownership of resources and the means of production?",
    option_a: "Capitalism",
    option_b: "Socialism",
    option_c: "Communism",
    option_d: "Mixed economy",
    correct_option: "Capitalism",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "What is the process of dividing a market into distinct groups of buyers with different needs, characteristics, or behaviors?",
    option_a: "Market segmentation",
    option_b: "Product differentiation",
    option_c: "Branding",
    option_d: "Market positioning",
    correct_option: "Market segmentation",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "Which financial statement provides a snapshot of a company's financial position at a specific point in time?",
    option_a: "Income Statement",
    option_b: "Balance Sheet",
    option_c: "Cash Flow Statement",
    option_d: "Statement of Retained Earnings",
    correct_option: "Balance Sheet",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "What is the term for the total value of goods and services produced by a country in a specific time period?",
    option_a: "Gross Profit",
    option_b: "Gross National Product (GNP)",
    option_c: "Gross Domestic Product (GDP)",
    option_d: "Net Income",
    correct_option: "Gross Domestic Product (GDP)",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "Which type of business organization is characterized by unlimited liability for its owners?",
    option_a: "Corporation",
    option_b: "Partnership",
    option_c: "Sole Proprietorship",
    option_d: "Limited Liability Company (LLC)",
    correct_option: "Sole Proprietorship",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text: "What is the marketing mix composed of?",
    option_a: "Price, Promotion, Product, Place",
    option_b: "Product, Profit, Planning, Positioning",
    option_c: "Production, Pricing, Packaging, Promotion",
    option_d: "Placement, Publicity, Profit, Positioning",
    correct_option: "Price, Promotion, Product, Place",
    subject_code,
  },
  {
    subject_id: "",
    question_text:
      "Which type of leadership style involves giving employees the freedom to make decisions and complete tasks on their own?",
    option_a: "Autocratic",
    option_b: "Democratic",
    option_c: "Laissez-Faire",
    option_d: "Transformational",
    correct_option: "Laissez-Faire",
    subject_code,
  },
];
